Carmen McRae Collection of Musical Arrangements and Other Materials
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Carmen McRae Collection of Musical Arrangements and Other Materials 1931-1993 (bulk 1950s-1970s)
ML31.M32
McRae, Carmen
approximately 1,000 items 41 containers 18 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Carmen Mercedes McRae (1920-1994) was an American jazz vocalist, pianist, composer, and recording artist. The papers chiefly contain musical arrangements and lead sheets for approximately 800 songs. While many of the arrangements include both full scores and parts, the majority are lead sheets or parts used for her small group performances. The papers also include a small amount of correspondence, photographs, song lists, program notes, and promotional materials.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Boland, Francy.; Burns, Ralph.; Carter, Benny.; Clayton, John, 1952-; Di Novi, Gene.; Holman, Bill.; Jones, Jimmy, 1918-1982.; Jones, Thad.; Katz, Fred, 1919-; Keating, John, 1927-; Mardin, Arif.; Matz, Peter, 1928-2002.; McRae, Carmen--Archives.; McRae, Carmen--Correspondence.; McRae, Carmen.; McRae, Carmen.; Nelson, Oliver, 1932-1975.; Pierce, Nat.; Rogers, Shorty, 1924-1994.; Sebesky, Don.; Simmons, Norman, 1929-; Wilkins, Ernie.
Subjects
Jazz singers.; Jazz vocals.; Jazz--Lead sheets.; Jazz.; Music--Manuscripts--United States.; Popular music--United States.; Women jazz singers--United States.
Titles
Carmen McRae papers, 1931-1993
Form/Genre
Correspondence.; Photographic prints.; Promotional materials.; Scores.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift; 1997
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Transfers
Sound recordings from the Carmen McRae Collection of Musical Arrangements and Other Materials have been transferred to the Library of Congress Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division. An inventory of this material is available in the Music Division's collection file.
Access and Restrictions
The Carmen McRae Collection of Musical Arrangements and Other Materials is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Carmen Mercedes McRae was born in Harlem, on April 8, 1920. She studied piano as a child and her parents encouraged her towards classical music. As a teenager, McRae wrote songs and pursued the jazz scene in New York City leading to a friendship with jazz pianist Teddy Wilson and composer Irene Kitchings Wilson. Through their influence, one of McRae’s early songs, "Dream of Life," was recorded by Teddy Wilson’s longtime collaborator, vocalist Billie Holiday. Inspired by Holiday’s depth of emotion and delivery of a lyric, McRae began to develop her own style and voice.
By the late 1940s, McRae was well-known among the young modern jazz musicians who gathered at Minton’s, Harlem’s most famous inside after-hours jazz club. This lead to recordings with Miles Davis, Charlie Parker, Mercer Ellington and others. The turning point in her career happened in 1954 when she made her first recording as a lead with Carmen McRae. She earned Down Beat magazine’s “Best New Female Jazz Vocalist of the Year.” McRae soon began recording with such major recording labels as Decca, MCA, Vocalion, and Verve. She recorded over sixty albums, toured the world, was heard on radio programs, and appeared on television and in films. McRae continued to perform until the age of seventy-one. Her final performance was at the Blue Note Jazz Club in New York. McRae died in Los Angeles on November 10, 1994.
Scope and Content Note
The Carmen McRae Collection of Musical Arrangements and Other Materials span from 1931 to 1993 with the majority of the materials dating from the 1950s to the 1970s. The collection chiefly consists of manuscript scores, parts, lead sheets, and annotated sheet music for approximately 800 songs. Notable arrangers whose works are found in this collection include Francy Boland, Ralph Burns, Benny Carter, John Clayton, Gene DiNovi, Bill Holman, Jimmy Jones, Thad Jones, Fred Katz, Johnny Keating, Arif Mardin, Peter Matz, Oliver Nelson, Nat Pierce, Shorty Rogers, Don Sebesky, Norman Simmons, and Ernie Wilkins.
McRae frequently performed with small groups, such as trios and quartets. She assigned numbers to the parts which refer back to her small group performance book. In many instances, these parts were taken from much larger arrangements. When applicable, these "small group #'s" are provided in notes in this finding aid.
In addition to the music materials, the McRae papers contain a small amount of correspondence, photographs, song lists, program notes and promotional materials.
Organization of the Carmen McRae Collection of Musical Arrangements and Other Materials
The Carmen McRae Collection of Musical Arrangements and Other Materials is organized in two series:
Music, 1931-1976
Miscellany, 1961-1993
http://lccn.loc.gov/2012563814
Container List
- Music, 1931-1976 (Box 1-40)
  Manuscript, printed, or photocopied scores, parts, piano-vocal scores, lead sheets.
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  - 500 miles high, Chick Corea / Neville Potter; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 1/1)
  - About Charlie, Louis Aldebert / Monique Aldebert; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 1/2)
  - About face, Peter De Rose / Charles Tobias; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Act three, Bill Comstock / Gene DiNovi; Lead sheet (Box-folder 1/4)
  - The afflictions of the times, Della Reese; Lead sheet (Box-folder 1/5)
  - African lady, Langston Hughes / Randy Weston; Lead sheet (Box-folder 1/6)
  - After dark, Caryl Young / Jean Galvis; Lead sheet (Box-folder 1/7)
  - After love, emptiness, Robert C. Thomas; Lead sheet (Box-folder 1/8)
  - After thoughts, Ray Brown; Lead sheet (Box-folder 1/9)
  - After today, Score and parts (trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-3, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano/conductor, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Jimmy Jones (Box-folder 26/1)
  - Alan, Christine Gardner; Lead sheet (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Alfie, Burt Bacharach / Hal David; Score and parts (production, horn 1-3, bass trombone, harp, piano, guitar, double bass, drums, percussion, strings); Arranged by Don Sebesky (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Alfie, Burt Bacharach / Hal David; Parts (trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-4, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano/conductor, guitar, double bass, drums, strings); Arranged by Nat Pierce (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Alfie, Burt Bacharach / Hal David; Parts (trumpet, trombone, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, piano/conductor, guitar, b, drums); Arranged by Norman Simmons (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Alfie, Burt Bacharach / Hal David; Parts (double bass, drums); Arranger unknown (Box-folder 1/13)
  - All by myself, Eric Carmen; Parts (vocal, guitar); Arranged by Dale Oehler (Box-folder 1/14)
  - All by myself, Eric Carmen; Parts (piano, double bass) (Box-folder 1/15)
  - All by myself, Eric Carmen; Sketch (Box-folder 1/16)
  - All I need is your love, Wally Putnam / Carmen McRae / Rick Huesman; Lead sheet (Box-folder 1/17)
  - All my eggs, Parts (piano, double bass, drums); Small group #22 (Box-folder 1/18)
  - All the things you are, Jerome Kern; Parts (trumpet 1-2, trombone, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, piano/conductor, double bass, drums, vibes); Arranged by Bill Holman (Box-folder 1/19)
  - All the things you are, Jerome Kern; Parts (vocal, flute 1-2, clarinet 1-2, bass clarinet, piano, double bass); Arranged by Fred Katz (Box-folder 1/20)
  - All the time, Bob Friedman; Lead sheet; Arranged by Benny Carter (Box-folder 1/21)
  - All through the night, Cole Porter; Parts (piano, double bass, drums); Small group #269 (Box-folder 1/22)
  - All too soon, G. Pocock; Lyric sheet (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Alone together, Howard Dietz / Arthur Schwartz; Score and parts (vocal, trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-4, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano, double bass, drums); Arranged by Ernie Wilkins (Box-folder 34/1)
  - Alone with my thoughts of you, Ronnell L. Bright; Lead sheet (Box-folder 1/24)
  - Aluminum baby, Jaki Byard / Fred Bouchard (lyrics); Lead sheet (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Am I blue, Harry Akst / Grant Clarke; Lead sheet and double bass part (Box-folder 2/1)
  - And I love him [her], John Lennon / Paul McCartney; Score and parts (vocal, trombone 1-4, horn 1-2, harp, piano, guitar, double bass, drums, percussion, strings); Arranged by Peter Matz (Box-folder 26/3)
  - And then there's Maude, Marilyn Bergman / Alan Bergman / Dave Grusin; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/2)
  - And watch the world go by, Margo Guryan / Bob Brookmeyer; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Angel eyes, Matt Dennis; Lead sheet; Small group #165 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Anthropology, Charlie Parker / Dizzy Gillespie; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Any old time, Artie Shaw; Parts (piano, guitar, celeste, bells, vibes, double bass, drums); Small group #149 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Anyone else but you, Steve Alan / Leonard Feather; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Anything goes, Cole Porter; Lyric sheet (parody), parts (piano, double bass); Small group #269 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - As long as we're together, Chuck Mangione; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/9)
  - At Christmas time, Tad Dameron; Piano score (Box-folder 2/10)
  - At long last love, Cole Porter; Parts (trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-4, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano/conductor, guitar, double bass, drums, strings); Arranged by Nat Pierce (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Autumn in New York, Vernon Duke; Parts (vocal, p); Small group #97 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Autumn nocturne, Joseph Myrow; Parts (piano, double bass); Small group #63 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Away, away, away, Bobby Troup; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Babe's blues, John Hendricks / Randy Weston; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Baby, baby, James Lipton / Sol Berkowitz; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Baby black, Gelsa Palao; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Baby blue, Stan Tracey; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Baby won't you please come home, Mack Gordon / Josef Myrow; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Ballad of the sad cafe, Charles DeForest; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/20)
  - The ballad of Thelonious Monk, Jimmy Rowles; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Baltimore Oriole, Hoagy Carmichael; Score and parts (vocal, trumpet, tenor saxophone, tenor saxophone "Ben," clarinet, piano/conductor, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Ralph Burns (Box-folder 26/4)
  - Bathroom window, Parts (double bass, drums) (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Be a sweet pumpkin, Ronnell Bright; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/23)
  - Beautiful moons ago, Oscar Moore / Nat King Cole; Lyric sheet and parts (piano, double bass) (Box-folder 2/24)
  - Bébado, Marcio Resende; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/25)
  - Because you're mine, Sammy Cahn / Nicholas Brodsky; Score and parts (vocal, trombone 1-4, horn 1-2, harp, guitar, double bass, drums, percussion, strings); Arranged by Peter Matz (Box-folder 26/5)
  - Behind the face, Jimmy Rowles; Lead sheet; piano part (Box-folder 2/26)
  - Better than anything, Bill Loughborough / David Wheat; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/27)
  - Better than saying goodye, Murray Grand / Tony Sibetta; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/28)
  - Between the devil and the deep blue sea, Harold Arlen; Parts (piano, double bass); Small group #46 (Box-folder 2/29)
  - Between you and me, Lynn Gibson / Bob Dorough; Lead sheet (Box-folder 2/30)
  - Bitter sweet, Nat Adderley / Carolyn Plummer; Lead sheet; lyric sheet (Box-folder 2/31)
  - Black and blue, Andy Razaf / Thomas "Fats" Waller / Harry Brooks; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 2/32)
  - Blame it on my youth, Edward Heyman / Oscar Levant; Score and parts (vocal, trumpet, woodwinds 1-2, horn, harp, piano, guitar, double bass, drums, percussion, strings); Arranged by Peter Matz; Small group #303 (Box-folder 26/6)
  - Bleeding orchid, Chick Corea; Piano score (Box-folder 2/33)
  - Blowin' in the wind, Mike Post; Violin part (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Blue Monk, Thelonious Monk / Abbey Lincoln; Lead sheet; lyric sheet (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Blue Moon, Richard Rodgers and Lorenz Hart; Double bass part; Small group #32 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Bob White, Johnny Mercer; Score and parts (vocal, trumpet, tenor saxophone, tenor saxophone "Ben," clarinet, piano/conductor, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Ralph Burns (Box-folder 26/7)
  - Body and soul, Johnny Green / Edward Heyman / Robert Sour / Frank Eyton; Parts (piano, drums); Arranged by Frank Collette (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Body and soul, Johnny Green / Edward Heyman / Robert Sour / Frank Eyton; Parts (vocal, trumpet 1-2, trombone, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, piano/conductor, double bass, drums); Arranged by Bill Holman (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Bows, Parts (trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-3, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano, double bass, drums) (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Boy, do I have a surprise for you, Gene DiNovi / Spence Maxwell; Parts (vocal, trumpet 1-3, trombone 1-3, horn 1-2, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, harp, piano, double bass, drums, percussion, strings); Arranged by Gene DiNovi; Small group #361 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Boy, do I have a surprise for you, Gene DiNovi / Spence Maxwell; Lyric sheet; piano part (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Boy from Impanema, Antonia Carlos Jobim; Parts (double bass, drums); Small group #164 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Breakfast in bed, Eddie Hinton / Donnie Fritts; Score and parts (trumpet, trombone, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, piano, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Arif Mardin (Box-folder 34/2)
  - Briar bush, Dave Brubeck; Double bass part and lyric sheet (incomplete); Small group #221 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Brubeck folder, Dave Brubeck; Lead and lyric sheets; Titles: Far more blue; Lord, Lord; Melanctha; Ode to a cowboy; There'll be no tomorrow; Travelin' blues; You swing, baby (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Burst in with the dawn, Al Jarreau; Lead sheet (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Busy, busy New York, Mary Lou Williams / Gracie Glassman; Lyric sheet (Box-folder 3/13)
  - But beautiful, Jimmy Van Heusen; Guitar part; Small group #73 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - But not for me, George Gershwin; Drum part (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Butterfly dreams, Stanley Clarke / Neville Potter; Lead sheet; lyric sheet (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Buy yourself a dream, Double bass part; Small group #321 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - By myself, Arthur Schwartz / Howard Dietz; Score and parts (vocal, conductor, flute, piano, guitar, double bass, drums, strings); Arranged by Bill Holman; Small group #167 (Box-folder 3/18)
  - Bye bye blackbird, Ray Henderson / Mort Dixon; Parts (vocal, trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-4, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Thad Jones (Box-folder 3/19)
  - Bye bye blackbirds, Parts (double bass, drums); Small group #120 (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Bye bye whitebird, Monique Aldebert / Louis Aldebert; Lead sheet (Box-folder 3/21)
  - Bye-ya, Thelonious Monk / Fred Bouchard (lyrics); Lyric sheet (Box-folder 3/22)
  - Can you tell, Margo Guryan; Parts (piano, guitar, double bass, drums); Small group #218 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Can't forget, Carmen McRae / Luther Henderson Jr.; Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Can't hide love, Sketch of lead sheet; parts (vocal, trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-4, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano, guitar/double bass, drums); Arranged by Gerald Wilson (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Can't we talk it over, Ned Washington / Victor Young; Piano part (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Carmen bows, Parts (trumpet 1-2, 4, trombone 1-4, woodwinds 1-5, piano, double bass); Arranged by Bill Holman (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Carry that weight, Score and parts (flute, horn, guitar, double bass, b, strings); Arranged by Arif Mardin; Small group #399 (Box-folder 34/3)
  - Catch a pebble, Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Cheat on me, Johnny Mercer / Gene DiNovi; Lead sheet; Laid in: note from Gene DiNovi to Carmen (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Chelsea Bridge, Billy Strayhorn; Sheet music; lyric sheet (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Cherokee, Ray Noble; Lyric sheet (Box-folder 4/9)
  - A child is born, Thad Jones; Parts (vocal, double bass) (Box-folder 4/10)
  - The Christmas song, Mel Torme / Robert Wells; Lead sheet; double bass part (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Cloudy morning, Joe McCarthy Jr. / Marvin Fisher; Score and parts (vocal, flute 1-2, oboe, baritone saxophone, horn, harp, piano, guitar, double bass, drums, percussion, strings); Arranged by Don Sebesky (Box-folder 27/1)
  - Cold September sky, Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Come Autumn, D. J. Andreas; Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Come cover me, Tommy Wolf; Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Come in out of the rain, Sketch; lyric sheet (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Come live with me, Caryl Young / Jean Galvis; Score, lead sheet, and parts (vocal, piano, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Johnny Keating; Small group #208 (Box-folder 39/1)
  - Come live with me, Score and parts (trumpet, trombone, tx, baritone saxophone, piano, double bass, drums); Arranged by Nat Pierce (Box-folder 34/4)
  - Come rain or shine - Pearl Bailey, Harold Arlen / Johnny Mercer; Score, vocal lead sheet; "Something wonderful" recording - salute to women of Broadway (Box-folder 38/9)
  - Come Sunday, Duke Ellington; Parts (guitar, double bass); Small group #279 (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Come Tuesday, Marilyn Bergman / Alan Bergman / Johnny Williams; Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Come with me now, Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/18)
  - Comes love, Lew Brown / Sammy Stept / Charles Tobias; Score and parts (conductor, trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-4, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Ernie Wilkins; Small group #94 (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Crystal silence, Chick Corea / Neville Potter; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 4/19)
  - Cutie pants, Steve Allen / Ray Brown; Drum part; Arranged by Norman Simmons (Box-folder 4/20)
  - Damn, this gittin' old is gittin' old, Bob Dorough / Lynn Gibson; Lyric sheet (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Darn that dream, Jimmy Van Heusen / Eddie DeLange; Double bass part; Small group #59 (Box-folder 4/22)
  - Dawn appears, Ronnell L. Bright; Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/23)
  - The day after August, Charles DeForest; Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/24)
  - Day by day, Guitar part; Small group #204 (Box-folder 4/25)
  - Day dreams, Carol Henry / Herman Foster; Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/26)
  - Day in day out, Rube Bloom / Johnny Mercer; Piano part; Small group #72 (Box-folder 4/27)
  - The day it rained, Duval Ferriera / Ray Gilbert; Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/28)
  - Day waves, Chick Corea / Neville Potter; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 4/29)
  - Dear death, Jimmy Woode; Score and parts (vocal, trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-3, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone 1-3, baritone saxophone, piano, double bass, drums); Arranged by Francy Boland (Box-folder 4/30)
  - Deliver the Milky Way, Christine Gardner / William Rubenstein; Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/31)
  - Desafinado (slightly out of tune), Antonio Carlos Jobim / John Hendricks / Jessie Cavanaugh; Lead sheet (Box-folder 4/32)
  - Desert air, Chick Corea; Piano-vocal score (no lyrics) (Box-folder 4/33)
  - Devil may care, Bob Dorough / T. P. Kirk; Parts (vocal, piano, double bass, drums); Small group #144 (Box-folder 4/34)
  - Did I ever really live, Parts (piano, double bass, drums) (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Did it ever really happen, Dorothy Beagle Helle; Lead sheet (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Didn't know about you, Guitar part (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Didn't we, Piano part; Small group #423 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Dindi, Antonio Carlos Jobim / L. Wolfe Gilbert / Aloysio Oliveira; Guitar part; Small group #409 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Do nothing til you hear from me, Duke Ellington; Parts (piano, double bass) (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Do you know why, Score and parts (conductor, vocal, flute, double bass, strings) (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Dodger blue, David Frishberg; Lead sheet (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Doin' all right, Guitar part; Small group #20 (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Dolores Gray [medley], Score; vocal lead sheet; Title: Give a little, get a little; "Something wonderful" recording - salute to women of Broadway (Box-folder 38/1)
  - Don't ever leave me, Jerome Kern; Score and parts (vocal, horn 1-4, alto saxophone, harp, piano, guitar, double bass, drums, strings); Arranged by Don Sebesky; Small group #317 (Box-folder 27/3)
  - Don't explain, Guitar part; Small group #327 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Don't get around much anymore, Parts (piano, double bass, drums) (Box-folder 5/11)
  - Don't go away, Parts (piano, guitar, double bass, drums) (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Don't know me, Parts (piano, double bass); Small group #9 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Don't pin me down, Leonard Feather; Lead sheet (Box-folder 5/14)
  - Don't talk, Score and parts (trumpet, trombone, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, piano, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Nat Pierce; Small group #355 (Box-folder 34/5)
  - Don't throw me away, Leontyne Watts; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 5/15)
  - Don't wanna tie you down, Lyric sheet (Box-folder 5/16)
  - Don't worry, Parts (piano, double bass); Small group #40 (Box-folder 5/17)
  - Don't you worry 'bout a thing, Stevie Wonder; Lead sheet; parts (piano, double bass, drums) (Box-folder 5/18)
  - Dream of life, Carmen McRae / Luther Henderson Jr.; Lead/lyric sheet; parts (trumpet 1-5, trombone 1-4, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by John Clayton (Box-folder 5/19)
  - The eagle and me, Harold Arlen / E.Y. Harburg; Score and parts (vocal, trumpet, tenor saxophone, tenor saxophone "Ben," piano/conductor, guitar, double bass, drums); Arranged by Ralph Burns (Box-folder 27/4)
  - Earthquake, Joáo Donato / Yanna Cotti; Lead sheet (Box-folder 5/20)
  - East of the Sun, Brooks Bowman; Double bass part; Small group #44 (Box-folder 5/21)
  - Easy as you go, Dave Brubeck / Iola Brubeck; Parts (piano, double bass); Small group #261 (Box-folder 5/22)
  - Ella Logon [medley], Score, vocal lead sheet; Titles: If this isn't love; Look to the rainbow; "Something wonderful" recording - salute to women of Broadway (Box-folder 38/2)
  - Elusive butterfly, Bob Lind; Score and parts (production, trumpet 1-4, trombone 1-4, alto saxophone 1-2, tenor saxophone 1-2, baritone saxophone, piano, guitar, double bass, drums, percussion); sheet music; Arranged by Shorty Rogers (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Emily, Lead sheet; lyric sheet (Box-folder 5/23)
  - Enchanting eyes, Lyric sheet (Box-folder 5/24)
  - Epistle, Leonard Bernstein / Stephen Schwartz; Lead sheet (Box-folder 5/25)
  - Ethel Merman [medley], Score, vocal lead sheet; Titles: Blow, Gabriel, blow; All through the night; Anything goes; "Something wonderful" recording - salute to women of Broadway (Box-folder 38/3)
  - Evergreen / With one more look at you, Paul Williams; Piano part (Box-folder 5/26)
  - Every day a little love, Joáo Donato / Norman Grimbel; Lead sheet (Box-folder 5/27)
  - Every day of my life, John Wallowitch / Tony Scibetta; Piano-vocal score (Box-folder 5/28)
  - Every man's got a woman, Trudy Rhone / Chick Morris; Lead sheet (Box-folder 5/29)
  - Everytime we say goodbye, Cole Porter; Parts (piano, guitar); Arranged by Luther Henderson; Small group #195 (Box-folder 5/30)